okay so here's the situation okay you're
all familiar with Obama's Iran nuclear
deal it's very complicated but basically
this is it everybody agrees that Iran
wants to eventually get nuclear weapons
right but this deal is just trying to
slow that possibility down in classic
cartoon terms they're just trying to
pour molasses into the Acme centrifuges
right that's basically what this deal is
now let's be H let's keep it 100 there
are intelligent Arguments for and and
against Obama's deal and then there's
this guy if you look at what happened um
with respect to the Iranian deal U the
only winner are the
Iranians that's right dick is
back yeah hey come on guys you know
there's something wrong with the world
when you lose John Stewart and retain
Dick
Cheney something not right oh and you
know what John actually warned me about
this in fact he left me a little
pamphlet about how to handle Dick Cheney
no he did he did it's right here it's
called John Stewart's guide to handling
dick not
U probably not the best title that's all
right okay uh number one uh make
immature dick joke complete okay did
that take a few deep breaths relax
penguin boys Obama's ban okay check that
out okay oh this is interesting it's it
says show any clip of Dick Cheney trust
me it will be
[Laughter]
bullsh no way that can't be it can't be
that easy all right roll 102 you compare
Obama's Iran deal to Neville Chamberlain
appeasing Hitler in Munich in
1938 really yes that is
bull joh was
right okay so so you're gonna open with
linking Obama to Hitler that's how
you're opening Billy Joel doesn't open
with piano
man did I just thinkink Piano Man to
Hitler sorry sorry Billy Joe all right
but maybe it got better from there what
else did Cheney have to say we did a lot
to limit nuclear proliferation in the
region while we were there but the
centrifuges went from zero to 5,000 well
they may well have gone but that
happened on Obama's watch not on our
watch no no no by 2009 they were at
5,000 right but I
[Applause]
I not right but hold on a second a few
things here number one you just got
caught in a lie okay number two you
didn't even act
cut right you acted like we're in some
sort of abusive relationship where lying
is to be expected right whatever baby
you knew I lied when you started going
with
me
come get me some
kavier and number three am probably the
most important if Chris Wallace hadn't
called you out on it you would have been
happy for everybody to just swallow that
poison pill
right like it was nothing a poison pill
that even Fox News choked
on well whatever it's just a
lie this is why it's hard to have an
intelligent conversation with this
impersonator of a human being Mr
Cheney it's one thing it's one thing to
not have a pulse anymore
but to not have a conscience is
unconscionable I mean guys he's just
like some creature who just makes
up and look I know it sounds like I'm
picking on Dick Cheney I know but
actually I have to admit some of this is
my fault um no no no I created Dick
Cheney all or more precisely um I
summoned
him I know I know I know it sounds crazy
I know guys guys okay okay this is a
story I never told anybody and please
don't tell anybody this is just between
us America okay all right all right so I
was like 9 years old at the time and I
was on
a I was on a hike in the woods and I
kind of got separated from a scout troop
and and that's when I met the talking
dog that I found out later was a
shape-shifting
witch but that's uh that's beside the
point really so anyway the dog led me to
an ancient cave and then he had me
repeat a spell in a language I didn't
understand okay but in my defense the
dog was very
persuasive summon the dark lord from The
Ether and you will get lots of toys for
Christmas
right if you've ever been in that
situation you know the rest a fiery
hellmouth opens a demon materializes the
talking dog rewards me with the kit Cass
Christmas and eventually the demon
becomes vice
president invasion of Iraq blame Obama w
w so sorry about that my bad all right
got that off my chest man that's great
yeah I just just emotional from the
catharsis so I apologize for that okay
all right so Dick Cheney expects us to
believe his pred about the Iran deal
when predictions are something he's just
not that good at simply stated there is
no doubt that Saddam Hussein now has
weapons of mass
destruction no
doubt um well if I could quote no doubt
don't
speak and it it's not even just politics
Dick Cheney has made horrible
predictions about all kinds of stuff
let's take a look at a few of them that
you're probably not even aware of I
predict that Bruce Jenner will never
ever be a
woman wrong
wrong it's weird it's kind of weird he
would weigh in on that during the
70s so I think we're all agreed that he
gets a lot wrong actually you know I
need to clarify there was one brief
moment when Dick Cheney got something
right uh it was in the 90s he supported
the decision not to invade baghad once
you got to Iraq and took it over and
took down Saddam Hussein's government
then what are you going to put in its
place that's a very volatile part of the
world and and if you take down the
central government in Iraq you can
easily end up seeing pieces of Iraq fly
off it's a it's a quagmire
yes that's right mother you predicted
the very thing that you ended up
doing so you knew it was wrong you knew
how it would end up and you did it
anyway you never apologized for it you
never your mistake and then you just
drop little lie bombs and and you try to
make the brother clean up your
mess you are living in an extreme
cognitive dissonance that not even bill
bellich would
recognize I did not conjure up Bill bich
you
guys all right now let's get back to
Obama's irand deal yeah it's complex
yeah it's just a lot of bad choices
here's former Secretary of State Hillary
Clinton's assessment without a deal
Iran's breakout time how long they need
to produce enough material for a nuclear
weapon would shrink to a couple of
months with a deal that breakout time
stretches to a year and that's someone
trying to make the case for
it right listen I don't love this deal
either but often you have to make deals
with people you don't trust when the
stakes are so high I mean sometimes it
avoids nuclear war like the salt
treaties with the Soviets and sometimes
they get you a kickass dirt bite for
Christmas like my deal with the witch
dog
again America I'm sorry but here's what
upsets me about Cheney I can't believe
anything he says when he makes
predictions they're wrong not to mention
he keeps predicting Obama will lead us
into disaster when one of our biggest
disasters happened on his
administration's
watch
okay
well I mean his and Vice President Bush
are so
[Applause]
so
yes so yes I do have questions about the
Iran deal we all do but I'll tell you
one thing if Cheney's against it I'm for
it we'll be right
[Applause]
back